weber.edu 2014-05-12

# WSU Privacy Statement

Weber State University has created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to user privacy. This document explains how we gather, use and protect user information.

**Personal Information**

While using this site, users may choose to submit personal information through email or online forms. We will use this information to process user requests, but we will not intentionally sell, share or distribute personal information to third parties except as required by law or WSU policy.

**Statistical Logs Kept**

WSU uses reporting programs to collect data about visitor traffic to our site. We do not attempt to personally identify visitors. Instead, we collect data to analyze in aggregate to determine trends and improve our sites. Here are some examples of the types of data we routinely collect:

  * Internet address of computer
  * Browser type
  * Referring web page
  * Date, time and duration of visit

**Cookies Used to Preserve Data**

Some Weber.edu sites require the use of cookies (bits of data passed by our network to the user’s browser for storage). For instance, Weber Portal uses cookies (active only during user sessions) to remember that a user successfully authenticated and to assist in page layout settings. Users are not required to use Weber Portal. This tool is provided for convenience. If users prefer not to receive cookies, they can turn them off in their browser or set their browser to ask before accepting new cookies.

**Security Programs Running**

We have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, to assist in maintaining data security and to assist in correctly using the information we collect online. We do not intentionally release personal information gleaned from these programs to others, except as required by law.

**Security Precautions Users Should Take**

Although we make every effort to secure our networks, WSU cannot guarantee the privacy of online communications. Users should use discretion in providing information in online classes, chatrooms or other open forums on the Web. If using Weber Portal to access personal records, users should be sure to log off when finished by exiting the site AND closing the browser. Failure to do so may result in the next computer user having access to the previous user’s information.

**Other Sites Have Different Policies**

This site contains links to other independently managed WSU sites. Some may use information for purposes other than stated above. Be sure to read their separate privacy statements. WSU sites also contain links to sites outside the University. These sites may have their own privacy statement or none at all. We urge users to exercise caution when providing personal data to any site. Check their policies and contact them if you have questions.

**Protecting Children’s Privacy**

We encourage parents to explore our website with their children, but we do not knowingly or intentionally solicit personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under age 13 has provided personally identifiable information to our sites, without verifiable parental consent, we will promptly remove this from our files. For more on children’s privacy rights, read about the [Children’s Online Privacy Act](http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm) at the FTC’s website.

**Alternate Ways to Submit Information**

Users have a choice about whether to provide personal information online. For other options contact the department responsible for the web page and learn how you can provide information by an alternate means. If users are unsure of which department to contact, use the WSU general information service at 801-626-6000.

**User Information Modification**

Users may review or modify their personal profile information (address, phone number, e-mail, etc) by logging into the Weber Portal and clicking on the Personal Profile Channel. If users wish to change their information through other methods (in person or mail) they may visit the Registration Office in the Student Services Center Suite 101 or mail a request to:

Registration Office   
Weber State University   
1102 University Circle   
Ogden, UT 84408-1102 

We will not accept personal information change requests by phone.

**Related Policies**

WSU policies are subject to change. We encourage users to check for updates on a regular basis. For additional questions about this privacy statement, we invite users to contact the Weber State University Webmaster at [webmaster@weber.edu](mailto:webmaster@weber.edu).
